Lev Karatun

Full-stack JavaScript developer

6 years of programming experience: professional development of a React + node.js application, teaching university students, and writing C++ as part of my PhD research. I'm passionate about modern technologies, website performance, and writing clean code.

lev.karatun@gmail.com

647-964-2973

Toronto, Canada

levkaratun.com

in linkedin.com/in/lkaratun

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-stack software engineer Bibliocommons Inc.

01/2019 - Present

Toronto, Canada

Building online library systems

Achievements/Tasks

- Develop front-end and back-end of a library catalog application (BiblioCore) using React (server- and client-side rendered), Redux, node.js, and Immutable.js.
- Created an npm package to standardize automated code linting rules for use across different teams, incorporated it in the CI/CD pipeline.
- Reorganized development environment which resulted in reduction of setup time from 30 to 10 minutes.
- Made multiple improvements to the application build chain: added webpack plugins to reduce the app bundle size, to enable use of latest JavaScript features and syntax.

Junior IT systems engineer CROC Inc.

10/2012 - 08/2013

Moscow, Russia

Achievements/Tasks

- Administered Linux servers, prepared technical and operational software documentation.
- Installed, configured and supported IBM middleware applications (IBM DB2, WebSphere App Server, MQ).

Application Support Specialist JSC "Raiffeisenbank"

06/2010 - 09/2012

Moscow, Russia

Achievements/Tasks

- Provided application support and analytics using SQL and Unix administration skills.
- Collaborated with QA and developers in registering and tracking bugs in the software.

PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

Movie data visualization (04/2018 − 10/2018) 🗹

- A dashboard visualizing movie data using D3 on the front end and MongoDB + Express running on node.js on the back end.
- Data is presented using three types of diagrams (scatter plot, map, bar chart) that allow for filtering and user interactions.
- https://github.com/lkaratun/visualization_dashboard

- A memory card game powered by React
- https://github.com/lkaratun/memory_game

SKILLS

JavaScript

React

Redux

node.js

Webpack

SOL

Python

Testing

bash

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Programming on the web (JavaScript) University of Toronto (Department of Computer Science)

09/2018 - Present

Toronto, Canada

Tasks/Achievements

- Teach JavaScript concepts, HTML and CSS responsive layouts, node.js, React and Bootstrap to students in tutorials.
- Decreased time spent on marking students' assignments by 80% by creating a suite of unit tests and integration tests using Jest, isdom, and Cypress.

Introduction to programming (Python)

University of Toronto (Department of Computer Science)

01/2014 - Present

Toronto, Canada

Tasks/Achievements

- Presented data structures and algorithms concepts to students in tutorials using Python.
- Taught students debugging principles in practicals.

EDUCATION

PhD candidate

University of Toronto

09/2013 - Present

Toronto. Canada

Thesis

- Numerical modelling of plate tectonics (C++)
- Contributed 8 pull requests to an open-source fluid dynamics modelling software (ASPECT)

B.Sc. and M.Sc. degrees Moscow State University

09/2004 - 06/2010

Moscow, Russia

Specialization

Computer technologies in geology

AWARDS

Laurence Curtis Teaching Assistance Award (2016) University of Toronto

Awarded annually to the most outstanding Teaching Assistants in the Department of Earth Sciences.